The word adversarial in generative adversarial networks means that the two networks,
生成对抗网络中的对抗一词表示两个网络
the generator and the discriminator,
也就是生成器和判别器
are in a competition with each other.
相互竞争
To understand this kind of competition mathematically,
为了从数学角度更好地理解这种竞争
we rely on game theory.
我们依靠博弈论
Game theory is a branch of applied math that was founded by
博弈论是应用数学的分支
John Von Neumann and later significantly extended by John Nash.
由冯·诺依曼 (John Von Neumann) 创建 随后经由约翰·纳什 (John Nash) 得以极大发展
Game theory can be used to model cooperation and
博弈论可以用于模拟在任何情境下
conflict between rational agents in any situation,
理性主体的合作与对抗
where each agent can choose from some set of actions,
其中 每个主体都可以从一系列行为中做出选择
and the choice of actions determines a well-defined payoff for each player.
行为的选择决定了每个参与者界限清晰的结果
Let's take the game of rock,
我们以石头
paper, scissors, as an example.
剪刀 布这个游戏为例
Each player can choose whether to play rock, paper or scissors.
每个参与者都可以选择石头 剪刀或布
That defines a set of possible actions.
这就决定了一系列可能的动作
Each player also has a payoff.
每个参与者也都有个结果
Let's say that the winning player receives a payoff of
假如说获胜的参与者得到的结果是 1
one and the losing player receives a payoff of negative one.
失败的参与者得到的结果是 -1
Rock smashes scissors, scissors cut paper, paper covers rock.
石头打败剪刀 剪刀打败布 布打败石头
It's also possible for the two players to tie if they both play the same move,
如果两个参与者都采用相同的行动 就会不分胜负
then both receive a payoff of zero.
他们都会得到结果 0
Suppose that player one always plays scissors and player two always plays rock.
假设第一个参与者总是选择剪刀 第二个参与者总是选择石头
Then player one always loses and receives a payoff of negative one.
那么第一个总是失败 得到的结果是 -1
This means player one could improve by changing their strategy,
这说明第一个参与者可能会改变策略 进行改进
for example, to play paper more often.
例如经常选择布
What happens if we adapt each player's strategy over the course of several games?
如果经过几次游戏 我们适应了每个参与者的策略后会发生什么呢？
If the players are allowed to randomize their moves,
如果参与者可以随机选择他们的行动
they will eventually reach an equilibrium where
他们最终会达到一种均衡状态
each player chooses their actions uniformly at random.
此时每个参与者都会一致地随机选择自己的行动
An equilibrium is an important situation in
在博弈论中 均衡是一个非常重要的情景
game theory where neither player can improve their payoff by changing their own strategy,
其中两个参与者都无法通过改变自己的策略改进结果
assuming the other player's strategy stays the same.
前提是另一个人的策略维持不变
In the rock, paper,
在石头 剪刀 布例子中
scissors example let's look at player one's options.
我们来观察第一个参与者的选择
Assuming that player two chooses rock,
假设第二个参与者一直随机选择石头
paper or scissors uniformly at random.
剪刀或布
Let's consider what happens if player one increases the amount of times they play rock.
我们考虑下 如果第一个参与者增加选择石头的次数
One third of the time player two will play rock as well.
第二个参与者选择石头也有三分之一的次数
That results in a tie where neither player gets any points.
如果结果不分胜负 两个人都不得分
One third of the time, player two will play paper.
第二个参与者选择布是三分之一的次数
So the increased amount of times that player one
第一个参与者增加选择石头的次数
plays rock will result in player one losing.
会导致他失败
Finally, one third of the time player two will play scissors.
最后第二个参与者选择剪刀是三分之一的次数
So the extra times that player one plays rock will give player
那么第一个参与者额外选择石头的次数会让他获胜
one some wins that exactly cancel out their losses from earlier.
抵消他之前的失败
Overall, player one got nothing from changing their strategy.
总之 第一个参与者改变策略后一无所获
We can make the same argument if we think about player
由于结果具有对称性 如果我们考虑第二个参与者
two since the payoffs are symmetrical.
也会得到相同的参数值
This equilibrium where both players choose their actions uniformly at
在这种均衡状态下 两个参与者一致随机地选择自己的行为
random is an important defining characteristic of the rock, paper, scissors game.
是定义石头 剪刀 布游戏的重要特征
We can analyze the game and conclude that
我们分析这个游戏 总结出
rational agents will learn to play completely at random.
理性主体学会完全随机玩游戏
To understand GANs, we need to think about
为了理解生成对抗网络 我们需要思考
how payoffs and equilibria work in the context of machine learning.
机器学习背景下结果和均衡的原理
If we can identify an equilibrium in the GAN game,
如果我们可以指定生成对抗网络中的一个均衡状态
we can use that equilibrium as a defining characteristic to understand that game.
我们使用这种均衡作为定义特征 来理解这个游戏
Most machine learning models we have seen so far are based on optimization.
目前为止 我们见到的大多数机器学习模型都是基于最优化
We write down some model parameters,
我们写出一些模型参数
we write down a cost function of those parameters,
写出一些参数的代价函数
and we minimize the cost.
然后最小化成本
In this graph we represent the parameters with the two horizontal axes.
在这个图形中 我们使用两个水平轴表示参数
The cost function is plodded along in the vertical axis.
代价函数沿着纵轴缓慢行进
The goal of the learning algorithm is to find a very low value of the cost function.
学习算法的目的在于找到代价函数的极小值
Usually we don't actually find a global minimum or even a local minimum.
通常我们无法找到这种全局最小值 甚至无法找到局部最小值
We get stuck in a place where numerical problems
我们会陷入困惑中
make it difficult to keep going downhill.
数值问题让它很难继续下降
But the optimization algorithm,
不过优化算法
more or less, does a good job of finding a point with very low cost.
在寻找最小成本的点方面可以做的不错
GANs are different because now there are two different players,
生成对抗网络有所不同 因为现在有两个不同的参与者
the generator and the discriminator.
生成器 (generator) 和判别器(discriminator)
Each player has its own cost.
每个参与者都有自己的成本
In one easy to visualise version of GANs,
在生成对抗网络易于可视化的版本中
the cost for the discriminator is just the negative of the cost for the generator.
判别器的成本是生成器代价的负数形式
In this simple case we can describe the whole game using a value function.
在这个简单的例子中 我们使用价值函数描述整个博弈
The generator wants to minimize
生成器想要最小化
the value function and the discriminator wants to maximize the value function.
价值函数 而判别器想要最大化价值函数
Recall that earlier we said an equilibrium occurs when
回想之前我们说过
neither player can improve their situation without changing the other player's strategy.
如果不改变对方策略 两个参与者都无法改进情况时会出现均衡状态
That happens when we are at a maximum for
当我们处于判别器的最大值
the discriminator and a minimum for the generator.
生成器的最小值时 会出现均衡状态
This kind of point is a saddle point.
这个点叫做鞍点(saddle point)
You can see here that the game plotted here has an equilibrium in the middle.
这里你可以发现绘制的博弈在中间有个均衡状态
One of the horizontal axes corresponds to the parameters of the generator.
其中一个横轴对应生成器的参数
If we take a cross-section along
我们利用生成器参数对应的
this axis corresponding to the parameters of the generator,
一个横轴上的截面
the equilibrium looks like a minimum of the value function.
均衡状态看起来像是价值函数的最小值
The other horizontal axis,
另一个横轴
perpendicular to the first,
垂直于第一个
represents the parameters of the discriminator.
代表判别器的参数
If we take a cross-section along this axis,
我们利用这个轴的截面
the equilibrium looks like a maximum of the value function.
均衡状态看起来像是价值函数的最大值
This gives us a good way to understand games played by deep nets.
这给我们提供了理解深层网络之间“游戏”的好方式
We want to find a point in the space of both players parameters that is
我们想要找到两个参与者参数空间上的一个点
simultaneously a local minimum for
可以同时是某个参与者参数
each player's cost with respect to that player's parameters.
每个参与者代价的局部最小值
If we analyze the game for GANs,
如果我们分析生成对抗网络的游戏
the local maximum for the discriminator occurs when the discriminator
判别器准确预测输入为真的概率时
accurately estimates the probability that the input is real rather than fake.
会出现判别器的局部最大值
This probability is given by the ratio between the data density at the input and
输入的数据密集度 数据密集度和输入生成器形成的模型密集度之和
the sum of both the data density and
两者之间的比率
the model density induced by the generator at the input.
得到这个概率
We can think of this ratio as measuring how much probability mass in
我们可以把这个比率看做概率在某个区域的质量
an area comes from the data rather than from the generator.
多少来自于数据 而不是生成器
If we use the mathematical tools provided by game theory,
如果我们使用博弈论提供的数学手段
we can show that if both networks are big enough,
我们会发现 如果两个网络足够大
then there is an equilibrium where
就会出现一种均衡
the generator density is equal to the true data density,
其中生成器密度等于真正的数据密度
and the discriminator outputs one half everywhere.
判别器输出一半的数据
Unfortunately, even though the equilibrium exists,
不幸的是 即使存在均衡
we may not be able to find it.
我们可能无法找到它
We usually train GANs by running two optimization algorithms simultaneously,
我们同时使用两个优化算法 对参与者参数对应的代价进行最小化
each minimizing one player's cost with respect to that player's parameters.
训练生成对抗网络
Unfortunately, these optimization algorithms
不幸的是 这些优化算法
do not necessarily find the equilibrium of a game.
不一定能找到博弈的均衡状态
A common failure case for GANs is that when the data contains multiple clusters,
生成对抗网络的常见失败案例是 数据包括多个集群时
the generator will learn to generate one cluster,
生成器学习生成一个集群
then the discriminator will learn to reject that cluster as being fake,
判别器学习拒绝虚假的集群
then the generator will learn to generate a different cluster, and so on.
生成器会学习生成一个不同集群 循环往复
We would prefer to have an algorithm that reliably finds
我们会倾向于利用一种算法
the equilibrium where the generator samples from all the clusters simultaneously.
能够真正找到均衡 使生成器同时从所有集群中采样
That is the key research problem concerning GANs,
这是生成对抗网络的主要研究问题
designing a learning algorithm for finding
设计学习算法
the equilibrium of a game involving high dimensional,
在包含高维度 持续性 非凸代价函数的
continuous, non-convex cost functions.
博弈中找到均衡
Hopefully some of you will have ideas for how to solve it and
希望你能够想到解决方法
unlock new applications that require very reliable learning algorithms.
解锁需要可靠学习算法的新应用